Consider the claw /klɔː  爪；螯，钳/.
Frequently found on four-limbed /lɪmd 有肢的；有翼的；有枝的/
animals around the world,
it’s one of nature’s most
versatile /ˈvɜːsəˌtaɪl 多用途的/ tools.
Bears use claws for digging
as well as defense.
An eagle’s needle-like talons /ˈtælən 爪/ can pierce /pɪəs  刺穿/
the skulls /skʌl头盖骨/ of their prey.
And lions can retract /rɪˈtrækt （使）缩回/ their massive claws
for easy movement,
before flicking /flɪk 弹开/ them out to hunt.
Even the ancestors /ˈænsɛstə 祖先/ of primates /ˈpraɪmeɪt 灵长类的动物/ used to
wield /wiːld 使用；行使；对付/ these impressive appendages /əˈpɛndɪdʒ 附加物；附属器官/,
until their claws /klɔː/ evolved /ɪˈvɒlv/ into nails /neɪl 钉子，指甲/.
So what in our evolutionary past led to
this manicured /ˈmænɪˌkjʊə 修指甲/ adaptation /ˌædəpˈteɪʃən/,
and what can nails do that their
sharper cousins can’t?
When nails  first appeared in the fossil /ˈfɒsəl/
record around 55.8 million years ago,
claws had already been present for
over 260 million years
in the ancestors /ˈænsɛstə 祖先/ of mammals /ˈmæməl 哺乳动物/ and reptiles /ˈrɛptaɪl 爬虫动物/.
But despite the gulf /ɡʌlf 海湾，深渊；隔阂，分歧/ of time between
their emergence /ɪˈmɜːdʒəns 出现，兴起/,
these adaptations are both part of the
same evolutionary story.
Both nails and claws are made of keratin /kerətin 角质/—
a tough, fibrous /ˈfaɪbrəs 纤维的/ protein also found in
horns /hɔːn 角，触角/, scales /skeɪl 鳞/, hooves /huːf  蹄 / and hair.
This protein is produced by a wedge /wɛdʒ  楔形物 / of
tissue called the keratin /kerətin 角质/ matrix.
Rich in blood vessels /ˈvɛsəl 血管/ and nutrients /ˈnjuːtrɪənt/,
this protein factory produces an
endless stream of keratin,
which is tightly packed into cells
called keratinocytes /kerətinəsait 角质化细胞/.
These high-density cells give nails and
claws their trademark /ˈtreɪdˌmɑːk 商标；特征/ toughness /ˈtʌfnɪs 韧性，坚韧/.
Since nails evolved from claws,
both adaptations produce keratinocytes
in the same way.
The cells grow out from the matrix,
emerging from the skin where they die
and harden into a water-resistant /rɪˈzɪstənt 有抵抗力的/ sheath /ʃiːθ  （刀的）鞘  避孕套/.
The primary difference between the
two keratin coverings
is really just their shape,
which depends on the shape of the bone
at the end of the animal’s digits /ˈdɪdʒɪt 手指，足趾；数字/.
In claws, the bed of keratinocytes  /kerətinəsait 角质化细胞/
conforms /kənˈfɔːm 使顺从；适应环境；（使）遵守 / to a narrow finger bone,
wrapping /ræp 包裹/ around the end of the digit
and radiating /放射； 辐射/ outwards
to form a cone/kəʊn 圆锥体/-shaped structure.
Animals with nails, on the other hand,
have much broader digits,
and keratinocytes /kerətinəsait/ only cover the top
surface of their wide bones.
It’s possible that nails have simply
persisted /pəˈsɪst 坚持；固执/ as a side effect
of primates /ˈpraɪmeɪt 灵长类的动物/ evolving wider,
more dexterous /ˈdɛkstrəs 灵巧的，敏捷的/ fingers.
But given what we know about the
habitats /ˈhæbɪˌtæt 栖息地/ of our primate ancestors,
it’s more likely that nails came with
their own powerful advantages.
High in the forest canopy /ˈkænəpɪ 天篷，华盖 苍穹；树荫/ where
these primates lived,
wide finger bones and expansive
finger pads /pæd 垫/ were ideal
for gripping /ɡrɪp 紧握/ narrow branches.
And nails improved that grip /ɡrɪp 紧握/ even further.
By providing a rigid /ˈrɪdʒɪd 僵硬的；坚硬的；严格的/ surface
to press against,
primates could splay /spleɪ 斜面，斜角 splay out 张开/ out their pads to
create even more contact /ˈkɒntækt/ with the trees.
Additionally, nails improved the
sensitivity of their digits
by providing an extra surface to detect
changes in pressure while climbing.
This combination of sensitivity
and dexterity /dɛkˈstɛrɪtɪ 灵巧 敏捷 /
gave our ancestors the precise /prɪˈsaɪs/ motor /ˈməʊtə/
control needed to snatch /snætʃ 夺取 抓住/ up insects,
pinch /pɪntʃ  捏，掐/ berries /ˈberɪ  浆果/ and seeds, and keep a
firm grip /ɡrɪp 紧握/ on slim /slɪm 苗条的/ branches /brɑːntʃ - bræntʃ美/.
The evolution of nails and the evolution
of opposable /əˈpəuzəbl 可对抗的,可对立的/ thumbs /θʌm 拇指/ and toes /təʊ 脚趾/
are closely linked.
And when our ancestors moved
down from the trees,
this flexible grasp enabled them to create
and wield /wiːld 操作；使用/ complex tools.
Even if it was possible for wide
fingers to sport claws,
their sharp points would’ve
likely interfered /ˌɪntəˈfɪə 干涉/
with these primates’ regular tasks.
Claws are ideal for piercing /pɪəs  刺穿/,
puncturing /ˈpʌŋktʃə 刺，戳/, and hooking,
but their points make grabbing difficult,
and potentially dangerous.
However, both claws and nails are
used in some unexpected ways.
Manatees /ˌmænəˈtiː 海牛/ use nails to grasp /ɡrɑːsp/ their food,
and researchers think elephant toenails /ˈtəʊˌneɪl 脚趾甲/
may sense vibrations /vaɪˈbreɪʃən 振动；感触/
in the ground to help them hear.
Meanwhile, some primates,
like the aye-ayes /aɪ/ of Madagascar /ˌmædəˈɡæskə 马达加斯加岛/,
have re-acquired claws.
They use these extra-long appendages /əˈpɛndɪdʒ 附属物/
to tap branches and trunks /trʌŋk 树干/,
while listening for hollow /ˈhɒləʊ 洞，窟窿/ sections
with their bat-like ears.
When they hear an opening,
they burrow /ˈbʌrəʊ  挖洞 / into the tree
and skewer /ˈskjʊə  刺穿；串住/ grubs /ɡrʌb 幼虫/ with their needle-like
middle finger.
We’ve only scratched /skrætʃ 临时拼凑的  抓；挠 / the surface of all
the incredible ways nails and claws
are used throughout the animal kingdom.
But as for which of these
adaptations is better?
That’s an answer we may never nail down.